KASUN

BAYWARDANA



SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

•	+6581503134
\bowtie	abaywardanakasun@gmail.com
in	Kasun Abaywardana
	05-07-1991

EDUCATION

Singapore

- B.Sc in Computer Science **University Of Colombo** 2012-2015
- Advanced Business Solution Developer Institute of JAVA Software Engineering 2012-2012
- Oracle Certified JAVA Programmer **Oracle Corporation**

2011-2012

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React JS, Angular 2+
- Node JS, Kony, REST API
- Java Script, Type Script
- JSON, Jquery, CSS, SCSS
- mongodb, Firebase realtime DB, AWS S3
- AWS Lambda, API Gateway,
- Cordova, React Native
- Bamboo CI/CD, Bitbucket, Azure devops
- JIRA, Confluence, Planing Poker
- VS Code, Xcode, Android Studio

SOFT SKILLS

- Analytical Thinking & Problem Solving
- Collaboration & Teamwork
- Leadership

• ABOUT ME

 $oldsymbol{\odot}$ Detail-oriented professional having 7 years of work experience in the IT Industry. Have in-depth knowledge in modern web design & development Frontend using React JS & Angular 2+, Backend development using Node JS with AWS Lambda, Firebase & MongoDB, and Hybrid mobile app development (Ionic, Cordova, React Native). A dedicated, self-learning, motivated professional, capable of working independently and an efficient team player with excellent leadership capabilities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER | NOV 2022 PRESENT Cognizant Technology Solutions, Singapore
- ASSOCIATE TECH LEAD | FEB 2022 NOV 2022 BISTEC Global Services (pvt) ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka
- SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER / FULL-STACK | MAR 2021 FEB 2022 Softcodeit Solutions (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka
- SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER | JAN 2018 FEB 2021 Payment Services (pvt) Ltd / SDB Bank (UPay), Colombo, Sri Lanka
- SOFTWARE ENGINEER | APRIL 2017 DEC 2017 Payment Services (pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka
- SOFTWARE ENGINEER | JUL 2016 APRIL 2017 Crowderia (pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka
- ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER | AUG 2015 JUNE 2016 Crowderia (pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

● XGOWHERE | JAN 2023 - PRESENT

Senior software engineer

- · Web-based application designed to conveniently locate specific places for general public.
- The application comprises of both backend and frontend components. The frontend was developed using React JS while the backend was created using Node JS, utilizing AWS serverless architecture. As part of the development team, I contributed to the implementation of both frontend and backend functionalities, assuming the role of senior developer for both components.
- TAFI | MARCH 2022 NOV 2022

Associate tech lead

- TAFI simplifies tax practices for users with features such as preparation, filing, payment processing, planning, record keeping, and compliance management.
- The application is comprised of three primary components: three client-web applications. The frontend was developed using React JS with NX console, while the backend was built using Node JS Express and MongoDB. As a developer and lead, I was responsible for overseeing both frontend and backend development.

LINKS

• GitHub: github.com/Kasun002

• Twitter: <u>@KasunLakmal16</u>

LANGUAGES

- English (Read & Write Fluently)
- Sinhalese

INTERESTS

- Play badminton
- Traveling
- Cooking

REFEREES

- Mr Jeewaka Iroshan, Senior Architect (Axiata Digital Labs), jeewaka@axiata.lk, +94773687753
- Dr. S.S.P. Mathara Arachchi, Senior Lecturer (University of Colombo), ssp@ucsc.cmb.ac.lk, +94718328650

• DECISION EMPOWERMENT APPLICATION | JAN 2022 - MARCH 2022

Associate tech lead

- Web application which enables high-level strategic goals beside tactical initiatives insights that inform decision making for the organizations.
- The web application was developed using Angular 12 and vanilla JavaScript, with the back-end utilizing .NET Core and SQL Server. As an ATL, I played a key role in the web-client development, specifically with Angular 12.

• AVATARIN | OCT 2020 - SEP 2021

Senior Software Engineer

- The platform is both web and mobile-based, and it allows physically disabled individuals to connect with robots in public places. Users can purchase a time-slot and then drive the robot through a mobile or web app.
- The project's backend is built on Node.js and MongoDB, while the web client is based on React and the mobile client is based on Flutter. As a senior developer, My responsibility for both the web client and backend development.

ONLINE BANKING SOLUTION | MARCH 2021 - JAN 2022

Senior Software Engineer(Full-Stack)

- Online Banking solution for credit union (USA) customers to facilitate online banking and specific third-party services.
- The application is comprised of separate web and mobile components, both based on a customized JavaScript framework (Kony). The back-end is primarily built on a Java framework (Fabric). My primary focus was on the web and mobile applications, with some involvement in the Java back-end.

• MOBILE PAYMENT WALLET | APRIL 2017 - FEB 2021

Senior Software/Senior Software Engineer

- The mobile payment platform enables users to make utility payments, access basic online banking facilities, and conduct secure QR-based payments.
- In this project, the mobile application's front-end is developed using Angular 4-9 with Cordova, while the backend is built on Java (Spring Boot), MySQL, and Firebase. I played the roles of software engineer and senior software engineer for both front-end and Firebase-based backend development.

● BP-SYSTEM | JUNE 2019 - JAN 2020

Software Engineer

- The simple web-based platform allows business owners to create their own business processes, and users can manage their processes on the platform.
- This project's web application front-end is built on React, while the back-end is developed using Java (Spring Boot) and MySQL. As a Senior Software Engineer, my primary role was front-end development using React

BACK-OFFICE ADMIN PANEL FOR MOBILE WALLET | FEB 2018 - MARCH 2019 Software Engineer

- · Admin panel is all based on back-office operations of mobile payment wallet.
- The application's front-end is developed using React, while the back-end is built on Java (Spring Boot), Firebase, and MySQL. As a Senior Software Engineer, I was responsible for both front-end and Firebase part back-end development in this project.

● MOBILE POS | FEB 2018 - JUL 2018

Software Engineer

- Mobile based POS system for QR payments.
- In this project, the mobile application front-end is built on React Native, while the admin panel is developed using React. The back-end is built on Java (Spring Boot) and MySQL. As a Senior Software Engineer, my primary role was front-end development using React Native.

• GRADE5 (EXAMINATION PORTAL) | AUG 2015 - MARCH 2017

Associate Software Engineer/Software Engineer

- Grade5 is a on-line examination portal for train student the grade 5 Scholarship examination. It Consist of Web and Android application.
- The web application's front-end is developed using Angular 2 with a module-based approach, and the back-end is built on Node.js and MongoDB. I fully developed the consumer front-end app using Angular 2 in this project.